&gt;&gt; So I've been working on neural networks since 2006 when I took
&gt;&gt; 私は大学院で初めてAIクラスを受けた2006年からずっと ニューラルネットワークに取り組んできましたが
my first AI class in grad school but neural networks actually have a much longer history.
ニューラルネットワークはそれよりずっと長い歴史を持っています
They go back all the way to the 1950s.
その起源は1950年代まで遡ります
&gt;&gt; That's a great point. One of the fascinating things about neural networks,
&gt;&gt; 大事なポイントですねニューラルネットワークの魅力の1つは
at least to me, is how long they've taken to become an overnight success.
成功を収めるまでにどれくらいの時間がかかったかということです
As far back as the late 90s there was a network called the LeNet built by
90年代後半に 郵便局と銀行が郵便や小切手の数字を読み取るために使用していた
Yann LeCun that the post office and banks used to
LeNetというネットワークがありました
read digits on mail and checks and it was incredibly important.
Yann LeCunが構築したこのネットワークは 実に重要な役割を果たしていました
But even after LeNet,
しかしLeNetが生まれた後も
not a lot of interest picked up in neural networks.
ニューラルネットワークが大注目を浴びたわけではありません
Deep learning has only really taken off in the last five years.
ディープラーニングは5年前に始まったばかりです
It's kind of a puzzle why it took so long.
それほど時間がかかった理由は何でしょうか
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a good question.
&gt;&gt; いい質問ですね
The answer boils down to the increased availability of
答えは 現代のプロセッサーの計算処理能力が大幅に向上したことに加えて
label data along with
ラベルデータの可用性が
the greatly increased computational throughput of modern processors.
向上したことにあります
For a long time, we didn't have
長い間 私たちはディープラーニングをするために必要な
the huge label data sets that we needed to make deep learning work.
巨大なラベルデータセットを持っていませんでした
Those data sets only became widely available with the rise of
このようなデータセットは 巨大なデータセットの収集とラベル付けを実行可能にした
the Internet which made collecting and labeling huge data sets feasible.
インターネットの台頭によって広く使用できるようになりました
But even when we had big data sets,
しかし大規模なデータセットがあったとしても
we often didn't have enough computational power to make use of them.
多くの場合 それらを利用するのに十分な計算能力がありませんでした
It's only been in the last five years that processors have gotten
プロセッサーが大規模なニューラルネットワークをトレーニングするのに
big enough and fast enough to train large scale neural networks.
十分な大きさと速さを備えたのは つい5年前のことです